1,200 years since Emperor Kammu
.settled on a location for his palace,
桓武天皇が往生の地を定めてより 千二百年
the city of Kyoto is now
.home to 1.5 million humans.
今日 京都の町には
百五十万の人間たちが暮らすという
But wait just one moment.
だが待て しばし
"Humans are naught but an
accompaniment to our history."
人間などは我らの歴史に従属しているに過ぎない
"We were the ones who built this city
and the history surrounding it."
歴史も町も作ったのは我々であると
Or so say a few big-talking tanuki.
大法螺を吹く狸もある
But wait just one moment.
だが待て しばし
"The skies above the palace have been
our territory since ancient times."
往生の地を覆う天界は古来我らの縄張りであった
"Fear and respect us
who dwell in the heavens!"
天界を住処とする我らを畏れ敬え
Or so they arrogantly declare.
てなことを傲然と言ってのける者がいた
The tengu, that is.
天狗である
Humans live in the city,
tanuki crawl the earth,
人間は街に暮らし
狸は地を這い 天狗は天空を飛行する
and tengu fly through the air.
Since the city's establishment,
平安遷都この方続く 人間と狸と天狗の三つ巴
humans, tanuki, and tengu have
.maintained a delicate balance.
That's what keeps the great wheel
.of this city turning round and round.
それがこの街の大きな車輪をぐるぐる回している
And watching that wheel spin
.is more fun than anything else.
回る車輪を眺めているのが
どんなことより面白い
I'm what you'd call a tanuki
私はいわゆる狸であるが
but too proud to be a mere tanuki.
ただ一介の狸であることを潔しとせず
I admire tengu from afar,
and I love imitating humans.
天狗に遠く憧れて
人間を真似るのも大好きだ
That's why my daily life is busy enough
.to make your head spin.
従って我が日常は目まぐるしく
In fact, there's no time
.to be bored at all.
退屈している暇が無い
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
面白くない世の中
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
omoshiroku sureba ii sa
this dull world more interesting
面白くすればいいさ
omoshiroku sureba ii sa
this dull world more interesting
“つまらねえ”のが口癖なのは
tsumaranee no ga kuchiguse nano wa
Some people love to claim that something is boring
sore koso honto ni tsumaranai
That habit is the most boring thing of all
それこそホントにつまらない
sore koso honto ni tsumaranai
That habit is the most boring thing of all
monku wo iu no wa kantan dakedo
It's easy to complain about stuff
文句を言うのは簡単だけど
monku wo iu no wa kantan dakedo
It's easy to complain about stuff
dareka wa nannmo kurenai
but it doesn't do any good at all
誰かは何もくれない
dareka wa nannmo kurenai
but it doesn't do any good at all
hashiranai kedo tomari wa shinai
That sort of useless waste of time
走らないけど止まりはしない
dare ni mo nagareru ahou no chi
runs in our idiot blood
誰にも流れる阿呆の血
sawageba sawagu hodo kakitateru
Just party on and on, and the more you do
騒げば騒ぐ程かき立てる
nanto subarashiki hibi
the more awesome will be your days
なんと素晴らしき日々
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
面白くない世の中
omoshiroku sureba ii no sa
this dull world more interesting
面白くすればいいのさ
jibun de mitsukerya
The things you find for yourself in this world
自分で見つけりゃ
hodohodo ni paradaisu da
quickly turn it into a little paradise
ほどほどにパラダイスだ
ki ga tsukeba itsu datte
Before you know it,
気がつけば何時だって
ki ga tsukeba itsu datte
Before you know it,
uchouten jinsei da
you live a life of pure ecstasy
有頂天人生だ
uchouten jinsei da
you live a life of pure ecstasy
Episode One
Goddess of the Noryoyuka
ん？
25th
Shimogamo Summer
Used Book
Fair
August
11th (Sun.)
- 16 (Fri.)
August
11th (Sun.)
- 16 (Fri.)
Big bro!
兄ちゃん
You're using that form again?
まーたそんな格好をして
If you keep changing your
.appearance all the time,
あんまりころころ姿変えたら
you'll get another earful from Yaichirou.
また矢一郎お兄さんに怒られるよ
Tanuki societal norms
.can eat dirt for all I care.
狸界の風潮なんぞくそくらえだ
But hey, did you need something?
それよりも何だい？
You're going to Master Akadama's place, right?
赤玉先生んとこ行くんでしょ？
Mom said to use this.
母上がこれ使いなさいって
Demachi shopping arcade
Masugata
She said she found it on the ground
.near the ticket counters at the station.
駅の切符売り場に落ちてたんだって
Don't tell me this is actually a leaf...
実は葉っぱでしたなんて 勘弁してくれよ？
ワン ワンワン
あー　あ ああ　う
グルルルルル
ん
あっ
See you later.
行ってくる
Demachi shopping arcade
Masugata
ん
ん？
ん んん　あっ
おいおい
ん く
What's with you?!
何なんですかあなた 大きな声出しますよ？
I'm gonna scream!
ああ 変態
Pervert!
-んっ
-あん
Quit messing around!
ふざけるのもいい加減にしろ
What are you even supposed to be?
何だその格好は
Just looking at you is embarrassing.
見ているこっちが恥ずかしい
Then don't look.
では見なければいい
屁理屈を言うな
Don't get smart with me!
Just think of it as a favor to Master Akadama—
これも我らが師匠
赤玉先生のためを思えば
Shut up!
黙れ
はあ それでなくとも俺たちは
As it is, we're already branded
as the pitiful children who failed to inherit
.the blood of Shimogamo Souichirou.
あの下鴨総一郎の血を引きそこねた
無念な子供たちというレッテルが貼られているんだ
ん
Tenkura
Just behave yourself until
.the Nise-emon election.
偽右衛門選挙まではおとなしくしていろ
Got it?
分かったな？　ん？
は
は はあ
うふふ
はっ
-く
-あああ
この く
はあ はあ はあ
はあ
Your daughter?
娘さんかい？
My kid brother.
弟です
あ
You airhead!
このボケナスめ
Did you really think such a cheap
trick would make me happy?
そんなつまらん小細工で
-わしが喜ぶとでも思うのか
-んっ
んっ
Master, I'm doing this because you
just sit here wasting away every day!
毎日毎日ぼーっと腐りきっている
先生のためを思えばこそ
I'm trying to breathe some
fresh air into your stale lif—
灰色の日常に一服の清涼剤として
I have no interest in seeing
your alluring figure!
お前の艶姿など見たくもないわ
Can't you comprehend the degree of artistry
achieved in this transformation?
この芸術的なまでに完成された
化け方が分かりませんか
Behold! This perfect swelling of the chest,
見よ
この完璧な胸の膨らみ
these slender hips, and these firm, pert—
腰のくびれ
ぴちぴちのその他もろもろ
Stop it. You're creeping me out.
やめいやめい 薄気味悪い
Sounds like you're just mad at
.yourself for getting turned on.
ぐっときた自分が許せないだけではないですか
There's no point taking it out on me, then.
ならば私に怒るのは筋違いだ
I won't be bewitched by the likes of you.
お前ごときの技量で
わしが化かせると思っているのか
Of all the impuden—
つけあがああ い い うう
じぎい あ うう
ふう　お弁当を買ってきました
I bought you some food.
Please eat up.
食べてください
んん
Have you seen Benten lately?
お前最近 弁天を見たかね
Nope. Haven't seen her in a while.
いいえ
ここしばらく会っておりません
She hasn't come by in a long time.
もう長く顔を見せない
I wonder how she's doing,
wherever she is.
どこでどうしているのやら
There's no way she'd want to
.come back to a place like this.
彼女がこんな所に帰りたがるわけがありませんよ
Is that so?
そうかしら
あ
I'm afraid I still can't.
私にはまだ無理です
ん？
ああ
What's all this, then?
それは何だ？
あ
んっ
Greetings.
罷り越しましたるは 下鴨総一郎の三男
I am Yasaburou, third son
.of Shimogawa Souichirou.
矢三郎でございます
I come bearing a gift for
.Nyoigatake Yakushibou.
如意ヶ嶽薬師坊様へ 献上の品でございます
My thanks.
ご苦労
フフ
ふう
はあ
You needn't have gone to such trouble.
ご苦労様でございます
What are you wearing?
その格好は何？
Is it strange?
あ おかしいですか
So, you're not human either, huh?
あなたもやっぱり人間ではないの？
I guess that remains to be seen.
さて どうでしょうね
And you?
あなたは？
I am but Suzuki Satomi.
私はただの鈴木聡美です
Don't tease. Just leave him be.
よせよせからかうな
He's sly, that one.
そいつは曲者だぞ
A real nasty fellow.
質の悪い奴だ
He seems interesting!
面白そうだわ
Him, interesting?
面白いものか
He's a clever one, for sure.
何でもできる器用者だが
He's capable, but he knows
.nothing of self-improvement.
己を正すということを知らん奴でな
He'll never amount to anything.
どうせロクな者にはなるまい
He seems quite fond of you.
随分お気に入りのようです
Don't be absurd.
バカを言う
Would you like to see the flowers?
あなたもご覧
I've never seen such a splendid
.cherry blossom tree.
こんな立派な桜は見たことがありません
あ
Hey.
おい
Why don't you try doing
what I taught you?
教えた通りにやってごらん
Goodness. You know I can't yet.
あら 私まだできません
Just give it a try.
やってごらん
ん
あ
I did it!
できました
We soar through the heavens
.wherever we please.
天空を自在に飛行する
That's what it means to be a tengu.
それが天狗というものだ
Disgusting.
んん
-不味い不味い
-あっ
This rubbish isn't remotely edible.
こんなもの食えたものではない
はあ
Let's get one from the
.same place next time.
次回もここのお弁当にしましょう
You ate half of it, so it must
.have been good enough.
半分も食べてるってことは
そこそこ旨かったってことだ
Is that any way to treat your master?
それが師匠に対する態度か
Whatever's cheap, as long
as it's "good enough"?
安物で済ませおって
Today is Friday.
今日は金曜日である
I daresay Benten is out
.with the Friday Fellows.
恐らく弁天は
金曜倶楽部へ出かけているに違いないぞ
She must be living the good life.
きっと弁天様も楽しくやっているのでしょう
What's so fun about hanging
out with those humans?
あんな人間どもとつるんで何が楽しいものか
Benten's human too, you know.
弁天様だって人間ですよ？
Or had you forgotten?
お忘れですか
She's always out partying late at night.
夜遊びばかりしおって
If I don't keep an eye on her,
she immediately strays from the right path.
わしが見ていてやらねばすぐに魔道を踏み外す
She's hopeless.
しょうがねえ奴だ
Don't you think "strays from the right path"
is a strange way to put—
魔道を踏み外すというのは
何だか妙な言い方では？
Quiet, you.
やかましい
ん
This place has better ventilation
.than you'd expect.
意外に風が通りますね
The only visitors I get these days
.are you and the bugs.
うちに寄り付くのは虫とお前ぐらいのものだ
How depressing,
味気ない
You could stand to be a little
.more appreciative, you know.
少しは感謝していただきたいものです
Oh? Who even asked you to come?
誰がお前に来てくれと言うたか
ん
You were such a troublesome student.
お前は全く厄介な生徒であった
I thought I'd finally gotten rid of you,
ようやくその面を見る面倒が無くなったというのに
and now you expect me to be happy
when you nonchalantly drop by?
今更のこのこ来られて嬉しいと思うか
I'm fresh out of lectures!
説教の種も尽き果てた
Don't they say that the worse the student,
the more the teacher loves them?
ダメな生徒ほど
先生には可愛いものだと言うではありませんか
Who would say that?
そんなこと誰が言っておるんだ バカめ
What nonsense.
Since you clearly have nothing better to do,
お前 どうせ暇であろう
ああ
why don't you go find Benten,
and bring her here?
弁天を探して連れてこい
No way.
嫌です
She won't come here, and there's
.no way I could convince her.
私が説得したって来やしません
Besides, I can't stand Benten
.or the Friday Fellows.
それに弁天様も金曜倶楽部も大っ嫌いです
Also, while you're out,
pick up a few cotton swabs.
あと 出掛けるついでに綿棒を買ってこい
When my ears itch,
my mood grows stormy.
耳が痒いとわしは辻風を吹かす
There's a fresh package
.on the washstand already.
綿棒は新品を洗面台に置いてあります
And besides, didn't I
just say I wasn't going?
私は行かないと言ってるじゃないですか
Hold on a minute.
しばし待て ええ 今手紙を書くとしよう
I think I'll write a letter.
Hmm, ben, ben, ten, ten...
ええ 弁…
You stubborn old tengu!
分からんジジイめ
Pipe down, clean out your ears,
and get to bed!
Err, it'd be better to use her real name here...
おとなしく耳掃除をしてさっさと寝てしまえ　ん
と 何だっけかな ううんと
What was it again?
はあ
Satomi
To Suzuki Satomi
う
Make sure you deliver this
.to Benten tonight.
今夜中に必ず弁天に届けい
Consider it your honorable duty.
名誉な役目と心得よ
はあ
I, Shimogamo Yasaburou,
accept this mission.
下鴨矢三郎
心得ました
Very well!
うんむ
ん
あ
あ？
This bow's just the thing
.for playing Cupid.
恋のキューピッドに格好の小道具なり
Demachi
shopping arcade
Chikurintei
Masugata Co-op
Seven Lucky Gods,
..Seven Lucky Gods...
七福神 七福神
あ
Looks like this is the place.
恐らくはあれか
肝心のが見当たらん
But I don't see the target...
ん？
いた
There she is!
Nyoigatake Yakushibou,
..of all people...
如意ヶ嶽薬師坊ともあろうお人が
Who is he, some dumb high schooler
with his head in the clouds?
これではまるで
夢見る阿呆高校生ではないか
あ？
ん
One shot!
我こそは
現代版那須与一なり
Like a modern-day Nasu-no-Yoichi!
はいや
おお
Wh-Who was that?
とととと
Are you okay?
いやあ
撃たれた
That was close.
弁天さん大丈夫かい　おい
危ねえなったく
ほんまにもう
ん
How awful!
やだわもう
へへへへ　ういー
Akegarasu
ん？
ここはお嬢さんが来るような
This is no place for a young la—
It's me.
俺だよ 俺
Oh, you. Sheesh.
何だお前か
You're using that form again?
またそんな格好をして
These powers were
.granted exclusively to us,
我々だけに許された能力を
so what's wrong with
using them however I like?
思う様使って何が悪い
If you're so good at shape-shifting,
化けるのが得意だからって
you could at least turn into
.someone fit to be here.
少なくともここへ来るにふさわしい格好をしな
偽電気ブラン
One fake Denki Bran, please.
I'll have an aka and shochu.
-私は赤割りを
-ん？
ひ
う　ああ
あああ
さっきのあれは何です？
What was all that about earlier?
びっくりしたわ
You startled me.
Master told me to deliver
.his love letter, so I did.
先生から恋文を届けるように言われて来たのです
You were all the way across the river,
川向こうからでは遠いですし
矢文で一つやらせてもらいました
so I took the liberty
.of sending it by arrow.
Are you looking for a fight?
ひょっとして私に喧嘩をお売り？
I guess you could call it a token
.of our love-hate relationship.
愛憎表現と呼ぶべきものです
Well, I enjoy making sure people
.looking for fights find them.
売られたは喧嘩は買うのは好き
Please don't.
買ってはいけません
大切な扇が台無し
You ruined my precious fan,
and the Friday Fellows are in an uproar.
金曜倶楽部も大騒ぎ
I said I wasn't feeling well
.and excused myself.
私 気分が悪いと言って出てきたの
If I had really wanted to
.hit you, I would have.
本当にあなたへ当てたければ当てておりますよ
ははは
I bet!
でしょうね
おほほ
う
Thwack, right in the eye.
こう目玉にぶっすりとね
I apologize for the fan.
扇のことは申し訳ありません
If you like, I can—
よろしければ私が
No thanks.
いいの
I'll be holding on to this.
これは私が持っています
恋文 読みましたか
Did you read the love letter?
Of course.
ええ　先生はまた駄々をおこねになってる？
I suppose Master is
throwing another tantrum?
All he does is gripe and moan.
こねてこねてカチカチになっております
He's so grumpy right now.
Sounds about right.
でしょうね
Well, it's been ages
.since I last stopped by.
もう随分と帰っていませんから
Couldn't you at least try
to show up once a week?
せめて週に一度ぐらい
帰るようにしてはいかがです？
That's not really any
of your business, is it?
あなたに口出しされたくないわ
こちらも首を突っ込むつもりはありません
I have no intention of sticking
.my nose where it doesn't belong.
そんなものは犬も喰わない
And even a dog would
.hesitate to sniff at this mess.
狸のくせに？
Funny hearing that from a "raccoon dog."
Do you have a problem with tanuki?
狸であったらダメですか？
だって私は人間だもの
What can I say? I'm only human.
あなたが喧嘩を売ってくれたら
But if you're looking for a fight,
I'd be happy to find you one.
私 喜んで買うのに
とんでもない
Of course not.
And then I'd catch you and make you
.into a stew for our year-end bash.
そうしたら捕まえて 忘年会の鍋にしてやるわ
You're always so unreasonable.
またそんな無茶を
It's a Friday Fellows custom.
それは金曜倶楽部の決まりだもの
At the end of each year,
we stew a tanuki and eat it.
毎年 年の瀬に狸を鍋にして食べる
ああ
マスター もう一杯
Bartender, another round.
すう すう
あ ああ
By the way,
ところで
あ
what's with the cutesy look today?
何故今日はそんなに
可愛らしい格好をしているの？
I wanted to add a bit of spice
.to Master's daily life.
先生の日常に
潤いを与えようと思いまして
What do you think?
Pretty cute, right?
なかなか可愛くできてるでしょう？
A beautiful display of
.master-disciple love.
麗しい師弟愛ですこと
You'd think, but he just
.yelled at me instead.
それなのにひどく叱られました
That selfish old tengu.
あんなわがままジジイ
放っておけば良いのです
You should just leave him be.
I can't do that.
そんなわけにはいきません
魔王杉のことを気にしているのでしょう？
Is the Demonic Cedar
incident getting to you?
あなたは気にしておらんのですね
It doesn't bother you, I take it.
Why should it?
何を気にするというの？
It's our fault Master
.can't fly anymore.
先生が飛べなくなったのは
我々のせいですよ？
No, it's yours for transforming
.into the cedar tree.
杉の木に化けたのはあなたよ
That was why Master
.fell and hurt his back.
先生が落っこちて腰を痛めたのも
But you were the one who
came up with the plan!
作戦を考えたのはあなたです
So what?
だから何？
はあ
これだから人間って奴は
This is why I can't stand humans.
You guys are way worse than tengu.
天狗よりもよっぽど質が悪い
Sorry to say it,
ごめんなさいまし
but you don't understand
.Master's feelings one bit.
でも
あなたは先生の気持ちがちっとも分かってないのね
南座ですよ
Minamiza.
That's where Master is.
先生はあそこにいます
ん？
うう
会うか会わないか
I don't recall saying
.I was going to see him.
そんなのはあなたの知ったことではないでしょう？
で 出過ぎたことを申しま
I-I'm sorry for my presum—
はあ す すうう
う
はあ
んん
How you managed to stay
alive this long is beyond—
お前よく命が続いとる…なぁッ
This is what makes life worth living.
これが生きがいでござる
ああ
Shijou Bridge
ふう　ん？
あ
ん
先生
Master...
よくもまあ
You sure have some nerve.
Wait a second.
ちょっと待て
I'm about to stand up, and if you don't mind,
I'd like to wrap my arms around you.
今すぐに立ち上がり
なんであればその体を抱いてやり
And then, if you don't mind, well, I think the two
.of us might take a leisurely mid-air stroll.
さらになんであれば二人で
優雅に夜の空中散歩へ出かけようではないか
You shouldn't offer to do things
you clearly can't, Master.
できもしないことを仰るものではありませんわ
お師匠様
おーほっほっほっほっほ
あれ
Ah.
おーほっほっほっほっほ
Oh, Master.
おや 先生
あ
こんな所で何を？
What are you doing here?
Oh, it's you.
何だお前か
Drunk, huh?
酔っておるな
ヘヘ
I may have had a few.
いささか飲みまして
You're always screwing around.
遊んでばかりおる奴だ
Well, I'm going to call it a night.
今宵はこれで切り上げます
まあ待て
W-Wait. I'm going home too,
so hail us a taxi.
わしも帰るからタクシーを呼んでこい
先生？タクシーなどよりも
Wouldn't it be faster to fly
there than to take a taxi?
空をひとっ飛びした方が早いのでは？
ん んん
あ
ああ
そんな意地悪を言うでない
No need to be spiteful.
This is pathetic.
全く情けない
My back hurts so much
.that I can't even move.
わしは腰が抜けてしまった
You idiot.
このバカめが 乙女の格好は止めろと言うたろう
Didn't I tell you to
drop the maidenly look?
I probably look like a girl who came
.to pick up her grandfather.
孫娘が爺様を迎えに来たように見えます
You still haven't told me what
.you were doing over there.
それにしても先生はあそこで何を？
ふむ
Yes, well, sometimes I like
.to have a drink in Gion.
たまには祇園で酒を飲もうと思うてな
Is that so?
そうですか
ん
Soaring through the heavens whenever we please
is what it means to be a tengu, right?
天空を自在に飛行する
それが天狗というものだ
そうではないか
しかし たまにタクシーに乗るのも
There's nothing wrong with taking
.a taxi every now and then.
悪くないのではありませんか
ふむ 悪くない
Yes, I suppose you're right.
Even we tanuki get sick of
transforming sometimes.
我々も化けるのに飽き飽きすることがあります
ふん 毛玉風情と一緒にする奴があるか
Ha! Think you can lump me
together with you hairballs?
かつて私は狸としていかに生くべきかという
Once, I wrestled with the difficult question
.of how one should live as a tanuki.
難問に取り組んだことがある
面白く生きる術は心得ているつもりではあったが…
I felt I understood how to
.live an interesting life,
but it was unclear what
.else I needed to do.
その他に己が何をすべきか 判然としなかった
And then, somewhere along the
.line, as I idled away my time,
そうやって何もしないでぶらぶらしているうちに
これはどうやら面白く生きる他に
I realized that living an interesting life
.was all I needed to do.
何もすべきことは無いようだと悟りを得た
がああ　ぐうう
くう くう う
かああ か
くうう くう　く
繋いだ手を振りほどけば
You shake off my hand
tsunaida te wo furihodokeba
いたずらに　君微笑む
and idly smile at me
itazura ni kimi hohoemu
春は嵐　ざわざわする
Spring is ripe with the roll of thunder,
haru wa arashi zawazawa suru
もう花びら散りすぼんだ
and some cherry blossoms have already left the branches
mou hanabira chirisubonda
口癖はケセラセラ
Your favorite phrase is "Que será, será"
kuchiguse wa que sera sera
また呟く声がする
I can hear you whisper it again
mata tsubuyaku koe ga suru
彼女はいつもさよなら言わずに
She always vanishes
kanojo wa itsumo
sayonara
without saying "Goodbye,"
iwazu ni
風と消える
just like the wind
kaze to kieru
I don't know what the future will be like,
mirai no koto wa wakaranai keredo
未来のことはわからないけれど
今ここにある奇蹟は僕のものと
but I'll have faith
ima koko ni aru
that little miracles
kiseki wa
are awaiting me
boku no mono to shinjiteru
信じてる
約束なんてしたくないけれど
I don't want to be tied down by promises,
yakusoku nante shitakunai keredo
but let's hold up our hands
sono te wo kazashite
その手をかざして確かなもの
and find something,
tashika na mono
手に入れよう
something permanent
te ni ireyou
それは僕らを輝かす
that will
sore wa
show just who we are
bokura wo kagayakasu
兄ちゃん大変だよ 雷様が来るよ
We're in trouble, big bro!
The God of Thunder is coming!
早く母上に知らせなくちゃ
We have to hurry and let Mom know!
Back in
the Game
Next Time:
Mom and Raijin, God of Thunder